Rodrigo Carvalho

Portfolio: https://www.rodrigocarvalhodev.com.br/

e-mail: rodrigos-carvalho@hotmail.com
Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/rodrigokrvalho
Github: github.com/Rodrigokrvalho

Cellphone: +55 15 99703 2347

Resume

Hello, I'm a software developer focused mainly on web applications in the Javascript universe. Since 2019, I have been studying programming and had my first exposure to the area during my Computing Engineering course.

I decided to focus on software development and started learning Java, creating an application called "Assistente de Cozinha" (only in Portuguese) that I published on the PlayStore. Since January 2021 I been dedicate to JavaScript and TypeScript, specifically front-end development using Vue.js, Reactjs and Next.js.

Also worked on some back-end projects using Express and Nest.js.

In July 2021, I made a career transition to work as a frontend developer, after working for 6 years in the sector forestry, where I was responsible for evaluating the quality of the entire Eucalyptus forest management process.

At Egos Soluções I worked for over 1 year as a frontend developer and 7 months as a full stack, where I helped with process development, participated in technical meetings with clients and collaborated with management and others departments to align processes and drive improvements in company applications.

Technologies

Front-end

Libries e frameworks Reactjs: advanced

Nextjs: intermediary Vuejs: intermediary

Styling

CSS: advanced SASS: intermediary CSS-in-JS: intermediary Tailwind: intermediary ChakraUI: intermediary

Back-end

Frameworks

Expressis: intermediary

Nestis: basic

Databases

Postgres: intermediary MySQL: intermediary MongoDB: basic

Mobile Frameworks React Native: basic

Experience

Full Stack Developer

EGOS Soluções Nov 2022 - Jun 2023 (7 months)

I was responsible for building projects involving the development of databases, APIs, PWAs and visual interfaces. In addition, I performed unit tests and application deployments. I was also responsible for maintaining existing applications, ensuring their functionality and performance, as well as how to provide training to the team and document the projects developed.

As part of my responsibilities, I participated in team alignment meetings to ensure progress tranquility of the project and the delivery of quality solutions.

The main project I worked on was a virtual menu for the waiter integrated with the Egos desktop aplication, our main challenge in this project was effectiveness communication between the web server and the local server, and the handling of information still on the front-end, where we leave some responsibilities on it to alleviate the load on the web server, even on the front we work on the information to only be validated in the back-end without the need for transformations.

In communication between servers, we initially decided to use a pooling technique to receive this data in the local server and information supply via a rest api in a multitenance multidatabase database.

Frontend Developer

EGOS Soluções Aug 2021 - Nov 2022 (1 year 4 months)

Responsible for front-end development of web applications:

Development of visual interfaces using Vuejs and Nextjs with performance and responsiveness where in some projects we work with mobile first.

Configuration of PWAs (Progressive Web Applications).

Handling data communication with the backend, both sending and receiving data.

Creation of unit tests.

Application deployment.

The main project I worked on was a web application for querying information that was supplied by the Egos desktop aplication, in this project, the main challenge was working on page performance and responsiveness,

mainly the dashbord graphics.

To improve page performance we work with data caching, we use break point techniques to better responsiveness and we use some graphic creation tools and in the mobile version we have further fragmented the information and graphics for better user visualization.

Field Technician

Eficiente Soluções Florestais Ltda Apr 2017 - Jun 2021 (4 years 3 months)

As a technician, I was responsible for conducting quality assessments and providing guidance to assistants in their execution. I also provided training for new team members. During assessments, it was my responsibility to provide feedback on improvements and issues identified during the evaluation.

I also assisted the occupational safety team in inspecting vehicles and teams, as well as providing safety training and guidance for process improvement to the entire quality team.

I participated in monthly management feedback meetings and shared information with other teams. I also attended alignment meetings with clients to enhance processes.

Field Assistant

Eficiente Soluções Florestais Ltda Jan 2015 - 2017 (2 years)

As a quality assessment assistant, I provided support to the technician in conducting quality assessments for various eucalyptus forest management processes. The evaluated processes included:

Seedling survival at 20 and 90 days.

Planting teams.

Mechanized and manual fertilization teams.

Mechanized harvesting teams.

Manual and mechanized herbicide application teams.

Manual and mechanized soil preparation teams.

Monitoring activities included:

Ant monitoring.

Monitoring of areas for weed control.

During these assessments, I assisted in data collection, documentation, and reporting of findings to support the evaluation of process quality.

Internship

IDEAS

Mar 2014 - Jan 2015 (11 months)

Floristic monitoring of environmental restoration areas in CCRG and Forest Inventory.

Education

Rocketseat

Node, React, Nextjs, React Native Set 2021 - Set 2023

Backend Development:

Frameworks: Express and NestJS Principles: Clean code and SOLID

Frontend Development:

Frameworks: ReactJS and Next.js

Important concepts: Server-Side Rendering, Client-Side Rendering, Static Generation

CSS preprocessors and styling tools: SASS, ChakraUI, CSS-in-JS

Mobile Development: Framework: React Native

Univesp

Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering 2018 - 2022

Fatec Capão Bonito

Associate degree in Forestry, Forest Management, and Natural Resources. 2013-2015

Instituto Politécnico Educacional

Technical degree in Occupational Safety.

2012 - 2013

Workplace inspection and evaluation.

Development and implementation of safety policies.

Investigation of accidents and incidents.

Training and awareness of employees.

Maintenance of detailed records and reports.